<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on ECE3SAT</title>
    <link>http://www.ece3sat.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on ECE3SAT</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.ece3sat.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to slow down satellite rotation ? - The B-dot algorithm</title>
      <link>http://www.ece3sat.com/blog/2018-01-25-how-to-slow-down-rotation-the-bdot-algorithm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ece3sat.com/blog/2018-01-25-how-to-slow-down-rotation-the-bdot-algorithm/</guid>
      <description>The primary purpose of the Attitude Determination and Control System (or ADCS) is to control the attitude of the satellite (as its name would suggest). In the case of ECE³SAT, this will be done by interacting with the Earth&amp;rsquo;s magnetic field.
How so ? By using magnetorquers, which are just some kind of coils used to produce a torque, thus so adjusting the satellite&amp;rsquo;s rotation.
Most certainly, the nanosatellite will undergo some rotation at various stages of its flight: upon separation with the PPOD launcher (or any other launcher) or when deploying the antennas or the Electrodynamic Tether.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a student-designed CubeSat made of?</title>
      <link>http://www.ece3sat.com/blog/2018-01-10-what-is-a-student-designed-cubesat-made-of/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ece3sat.com/blog/2018-01-10-what-is-a-student-designed-cubesat-made-of/</guid>
      <description>Building a satellite is a big adventure for students like us! Even so this enterprise could seem demanding and perhaps even intimidating, we have to manage this just as any other project. And it starts with defining what are the system functionalities.
Actually, there are a few standard core functionalities in the world of nanosatellites:
 First of all, as any other device, the satellite needs power to work. Electricity is produced by solar panels and distributed in the whole CubeSat.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>